Guide to the Publius Virgilius Rogers papers,1843-1918.
Rogers, Publius Virgilius papers, 1843-1918.
- Series I. Pamphlets
  - Constitution and By-Laws of the Colonial Dames of the State of New York (Box 4)
  - Comedie-francaise (Box 4)
  - An Act to Establish a General System of Banking, February 15, 1851 (Box 4)
  - Speech of Hon. Ellis H. Roberts, of N.Y. in the House of Representatives, April 30, 1782 (Box 4)
  - Supreme Court of the State of New York; D. Pratt, Justice, 1854 (Box 4)
  - Auction Sale: Catalogue of Valuable Private Library (Box 4)
  - In the Senate of the U.S., An Act, July 1, 1864 (Box 4)
  - How to Get There by the Steamships of the North German Lloyd (Box 4)
  - Report of Gilbert L. Wilson; Special agent appointed by D.B. St. John, Superintendent of the bank department to examine into the affairs of the Merchants' and Mechanics' Bank of Oswego, 1854 (Box 4)
  - Verzeihniss der Vorlesungen (Box 4)
  - Our National and Financial Future, Address of Hon. Hugh McCulloch, Secretary of the Treasury at Fort Wayne, Indiana, October 11, 1865 (Box 4)
  - D.C. Pierces Improvements in Rails in Railways, 1865 (Box 4)
  - Directory of the Offices and Students of Harvard University, October 6, 1887 (Box 4)
  - The Kirmess Spectator, Pardon and Kirmess, Utica Opera House, October 20-25, 1890 (Box 4)
  - Chicago Relief, First Special Report of the Chicago Relief and Aid Society, 1871 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of Imported Books and Second-hand and scarce books (Box 4)
  - Short List of Rare Books, June 1893 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report with the Compliments of the Treasurer of the U.S., June 30, 1877 (Box 4)
  - National Currency Act, 1863 (Box 4)
  - Illustrated Description of the Ho-o-den (Phoenix Hall) at the World's Columbian Exposition (Box 5)
  - Coronado Beach, "An Unique Corner of the Earth" (Box 5)
  - Twenty-Eighth Annual Report of the Board of Directors of the New York Central and Hudson River Railroad Company and its leased lines to the Stockholders, June 30, 1897 (Box 5)
  - Wines, How to Keep and Use Them (Box 5)
  - Practical Banking (Box 5)
  - The Aneroid Barometer, How to Buy and Use It (Box 5)
  - The Toynbee Record, September 1889 (Box 5)
  - Towns and Landscapes of All the World (Box 5)
  - Supreme Court of the U.S., Russell Sage, etc. vs. Central Railroad Co. (Box 5)
  - Various Pamphlets (Box 26)
- Series II. Volumes, Ledgers, and Books
  - Two Letter Books - Class notes of Charles B. Rogers for "Philosophy I," Oct. 1, 1887-May 31, 1888, approx. 200 pages, and for "Political Economics," 1886-1887. Hamilton College, 1886-1888 (Box 4)
  - Two Volumes (Box 5)
  - Ledger containing expenses of an unknown person, December 1903-January 1905 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook of Charles B. Rogers, tracing his school career from 1879, until his graduation from Hamilton College in June 1887?, with notes for debates loose in back, 1879-1887 (Box 5)
  - Four Manuscript Volumes (Box 6)
  - One recipe book, clippings, handwritten, etc. (Box 6)
  - Two Letter Books, April 10, 1871-November 11, 1887 (Box 6)
  - One Check Register of P.V. Rogers, March 31, 1871-October 28, 1875 (Box 6)
  - Cancelled Checks of Publius V. and Elizabeth B. Rogers, 1868-1905 (Box 6)
  - Account books (Box 25)
  - Two notebooks dealing with Central Railway Company of Iowa Investments, 1871-1895 (Box 25)
  - Two Notebooks dealing with Flint and Pere Marquette Railway Investments, 1871-1879 (Box 25)
  - Ten Bank Books (all sizes) (Box 25)
  - Three Notebooks - One of land grants, one of the Republican Committee, and one of miscellaneous securities (Box 25)
  - "Occupation Book" (Box 25)
  - "Personal Recollections of Whittier," by Mary B. Claflin (Box 25)
  - Record of New York State Court of Appeals, 1857 (Box 25)
  - "Butcher" Book, 1898-1902 (Box 25)
  - Three Household Account Books of Elizabeth Rogers, 1875-1903 (Box 25)
  - Eighteen small check books (Box 26)
  - Notebooks (Box 26)
  - Cash books (Box 26)
  - Cancelled Checks, c. 1868-1905 (Box 27)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - November 1843-December 1869 (529 Pieces) (Box 7)
  - 1870 (446 Pieces) (Box 8)
    Correspondence is mainly concerned with stock and bond purchases in railroads. The Central railroad Company of Iowa and Flint and Pere Marquette Railway, Saginaw, Michigan. (H.C. Potter, Secretary-Treasurer)
  - 1871 (426 Pieces) (Box 9)
  - 1872-1873 (342 Pieces) (Box 10)
  - 1873-1874 (491 Pieces) (Box 11)
  - 1875 (455 Pieces) (Box 12)
  - 1876 (521 Pieces) (Box 13)
  - 1877-1878 (c. 500 Pieces) (Box 14)
  - 1879-1880 (400-500 Pieces) (Box 15)
  - 1880-1881 (400-500 Pieces) (Box 16)
  - June 7, 1882-December 26, 1886 (400-500 Pieces) (Box 17)
    Letters are from banks and investment houses primarily, with a few letters from railroads. More personal correspondence and household purchases
  - 1887-1890(300-400 Pieces) (Box 18)
    Letters from son, Charles B. Rogers at Hamilton College. Investment news, mainly from Piers Brothers (The Patent Cereals Co.), N.Y., N.Y.
  - 1891-1895 (400-500 Pieces) (Box 19)
  - 1896-1903 (400-500 Pieces) (Box 20)
    Includes receipts
  - Purchase receipts, January 1, 1904-April 1906, 1904-1906 (Box 21)
  - Series of eighty letters from son Charles Rogers from various cities in Europe; Approx. 200 undated pieces, April 27, 1888-August 18, 1889 (Box 21)
  - Letters to Charles B. Rogers mainly concerning his dairy operations near Utica, 1909-1918 (Box 22)
  - Various Letters, Undated (Box 23-24)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - Loose Items (Box 6)
  - Typed and printed chapters to a book, broadsides, genealogy, contracts, bonds, misc. manuscript material, Undated (Box 23-24)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 26)
  - Photographs and postcards (European) (Box 26)